<resources>
    <string name="app_name">NobelPrizeViewer</string>

    <string name="phys_btn_text">Physics</string>
    <string name="med_btn_text">Medicine</string>
    <string name="pce_btn_text">Peace</string>
    <string name="chem_btn_text">Chemistry</string>

    <string name="detail_tab">NobelPrizeViewer:Details</string>

    <string name="default_detail">No Category Selected</string>

    <string name="default_name">Unknown</string>

    <string name="physics_detail">(French: [ʒeʁaʁ muʁu]; born 22 June 1944) is a French scientist and pioneer in the field of electrical engineering and lasers. He was awarded a Nobel Prize in Physics in 2018, along with Donna Strickland, for the invention of chirped pulse amplification, a technique later used to create ultrashort-pulse, very high-intensity (petawatt) laser pulses. In 1994, Mourou and his team at the University of Michigan discovered that the balance between the self-focusing refraction and self-attenuating diffraction by ionization and rarefaction of a laser beam of terawatt intensities in the atmosphere creates \"filaments\" which act as waveguides for the beam thus preventing divergence.</string>
    <string name="medicine_detail">(本庶 佑 Honjo Tasuku, born January 27, 1942) is a Japanese immunologist, and Nobel laureate best known for his identification of Programmed Cell Death Protein 1 (PD-1). He is also known for his molecular identification of cytokines: IL-4 and IL-5, as well as the discovery of Activation-induced Cytidine Deaminase (AID) that is essential for class switch recombination and somatic hypermutation.</string>
    <string name="peace_detail">(Arabic: نادية مراد باسي طه; born 1993 in Kojo, Sinjar, Iraq) is a Iraqi Yazidi human rights activist who lives in Germany. In 2014 she was kidnapped from her hometown Kojo and held by the Islamic State for three months. In 2018, she and Denis Mukwege were jointly awarded the Nobel Peace Prize for \"their efforts to end the use of sexual violence as a weapon of war and armed conflict\". She is the first Iraqi to be awarded a Nobel prize. Murad is the founder of Nadia\'s Initiative, an organization dedicated to \"helping women and children victimized by genocide, mass atrocities, and human trafficking to heal and rebuild their lives and communities\".</string>
    <string name="chemistry_detail">Sir Gregory Paul Winter CBE FRS FMedSci (born 14 April 1951) is a Nobel Prize-winning British biochemist best known for his work on the therapeutic use of monoclonal antibodies. His research career has been based almost entirely at the MRC Laboratory of Molecular Biology and the MRC Centre for Protein Engineering, in Cambridge, England. He is credited with invented techniques to both humanise (1986) and, later, to fully humanise using phage display, antibodies for therapeutic uses. Previously, antibodies had been derived from mice, which made them difficult to use in human therapeutics because the human immune system had anti-mouse reactions to them. For these developments Winter was awarded the 2018 Nobel Prize in Chemistry along with George Smith and Frances Arnold.</string>
</resources>
